# SATYAM MITTAL

# PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Creative software engineer proficient with Java, backend development. Experienced in developing backend applications and have 3 years of work experience. Looking forward to land a tough job in a reputed company so I can increase my knowledge and learnings.

# EXPERIENCE

# Teaching Instructor, 01/2022 to Current

#### Fresno State - Fresno, CA

- · Algorithms and Data Structures-CSCI 115
- · Introduction to Software Engineering CSCI-150
- Leading weekly Labs and aiding students in assignments and data structure concepts
- · Holding weekly Office hours

#### Student Assistant Web Developer, 11/2021 to Current

#### Fresno State - Fresno

· Developing website for KIND Program funded by NSF-ADVANCE grant.

### Senior Software Engineer, 09/2019 to 08/2021

#### Paytm - Noida, Uttar Pradesh

- Contributed to merchant on-boarding solutions by developing new features and enhancing existing one
- Worked on system stability and monitoring system API using monitoring tools like
   Grafana
- Designed REST web services and developing efficient algorithms to expedite processing of business logic
- Integrated Paytm payment gateway to onboard

### **Technical-Associate**, 06/2018 to 09/2019

# Zillious Solution Private Limited - Delhi

- Managed end-to-end development of two B2B online booking products, Insurance, and Bus
- Implemented social login (i.e
- · Single sign-on) on booking page for end users
- Developed an OCR reader using machine learning to parse receipts for expense management tool
- · Designed custom job batch framework for OCR reader using executor framework

# Intern, 06/2017 to 08/2017

#### Zillious Solution Private Limited - Delhi

 Developed an ERP tool to manage Zillious employee day to day track of biometric attendance and leaves tracker following hierarchical approval of leaves and attendance approval.

# CONTACT

Address: Fresno, CA 93710

Email: satyam05@mail.fresnostate.edu

**LinkedIn:** Online Digital Resume **WWW:** Online Digital Resume

# SKILLS

- · Languages: Java, Python, C++, MySQL, Bootstrap
- · Frameworks: JUnit, Spring, JS
- · Developer Tools: Git, IntelliJ, Eclipse
- Others: Data Structures and Algorithm, Redis, Design Patterns, Maven

#### **EDUCATION**

Master of Science, Computer Science, Expected in 05/2023 California State University - Fresno - Fresno, CA

B.E, Computer Science and Engineering, 05/2018

Sant Longowal Institute Of Engineering & Technology Punjab, India